- [somber music playing]
- [Moon Baek groans]
How are you feeling?
Hmm?
Oh, yeah. Uh, not bad. Considering…
I wanted to ask,
what happened when you were young?
Hmm?
You said your mom passed away.
[somber music continues]
[sighs]
Someone broke into our house.
Everyone in my family died.
I was the only survivor.
If my brother were still alive…
he'd be about your age by now.
You ever consider getting revenge?
I mean,
you could've if you really wanted to.
You could've found the guy,
hunted him down, and bang!
Shot him where he stands.
Not worth it.
[sighs]
What are you trying to say?
That you're better than all that?
Above us all?
Him being brought to justice
by the legal system
was enough for you?
That's why you became a cop?
[somber music continues]
People like that don't change.
It's not that simple.
The bastards who stole away my childhood
would've done it regardless.
If it wasn't me,
it would've been some other poor kid.
Revenge isn't always the right choice.
Especially if it destroys you. [sighs]
[gun clicks]
[gunshot echoing]
[music fades]
[sighs]
It all happened so fast.
I still can't believe it's real.
[sniffles]
[somber music playing]
[sighs]
[music turns uneasy]
Jake just reached out to us.
Why?
There are a few parties interested
in what's happening in Korea.
They'd like to get in touch with us.
Tell him I'll decide
after meeting them personally.
Good, sir. He was quite worried.
About what?
Me or the business?
[phone buzzes]
[uneasy music continues]
REPORTER WANG DAE-HYEON
I THINK THERE'S SOMETHING YOU SHOULD KNOW
LEE DO IS AWAKE
[music fades]
[Do] Thank you for coming.
[man 1] Years ago,
when Do and I were on a mission
in a region of the Middle East…
[sighs]
…we saw both adults
and children holding guns,
weapons piled on top of each other,
and I wondered,
"What would happen if that kind of thing
happened here, in Korea?"
[chuckles softly] Back then,
I couldn't even have imagined it.
Not for a second. And now…
So? How's the gun retrieval coming along?
Well, we pivoted the investigation
in a new way after the first few killings.
We realized that now
they were using real courier services.
They had an innate understanding
of the nature of the Korean people
and its infrastructure.
We estimate, in the past few days,
that about 10,000 guns
have been distributed to the public.
It was probably instigated
after the footage of you getting shot
was aired on social media.
[man 1] That probably managed to enhance
people's fear.
If you don't wanna end up shot,
you need to protect yourself.
That's what guns do.
False sense of security.
That's right.
They truly believe
no one else can protect them,
so they need to do it for themselves.
And for that,
they need a gun in their hand.
[brooding music playing]
Uh, Manager, there's something important
for you to look at.
[keys tapping]
A GATHERING OF SUPPORTERS
OF GUN OWNERSHIP LEGALIZATION
This began circulating on social media
a while ago.
It's been shared over 300,000 times, sir.
[phone buzzing]
Yes, Director?
The president's ready
to address the nation.
If he decides to declare martial law.
Korea will once again become
a country ruled by guns.
Okay, listen close.
We need all of you working on this.
It's top-tier priority.
We need to find out
who's organizing this rally.
If it becomes too large-scale,
all hell could break loose.
[all] Understood, sir.
[phone buzzes]
Huh.
What's wrong? What is it?
[man 2] Look at this.
What the hell?
[man 1 scoffs]
A pro-gun ownership rally?
A gathering like this will only lead
to more people getting hurt.
[crowd chanting indistinctly]
The unprecedented occurrence
of mass shootings
and the widespread distribution of guns
from unknown parties
has led to calls for Korea
to legalize gun ownership.
And pro-gun protesters
have organized themselves
to make their voices heard
by the government today.
In response, anti-gun protesters
have organized a counter rally,
leading to concerns that a major clash
may break out between the two groups.
Have any of you actually been shot?
I was shot and nearly fucking died.
I was lucky to keep my arm!
We've been living our lives
just fine without guns!
You actually believe having no guns
will keep you safer
than you were before, huh?!
Our future's at stake!
We need to keep our families safe!
We don't want guns in our lives ever!
- Legalize guns!
- [chanting] Never! Never!
- [chanting] Legalize! Legalize! Legalize!
- [chanting] Never! Never! Never!
[phone buzzing]
Hi, Mom.
Hey, honey. Are you still working?
Mm-hmm.
I'm working night shifts again this week.
Oh. And you're doing okay?
Of course. Why wouldn't I be okay?
I heard on the news
about a lot of people getting shot lately.
It must be quite chaotic
at your hospital right now.
Mom, I have to get back to work.
Can I call you later?
[sighs] Okay.
[Do] Officer Jang,
I need to get to that rally.
I promise you,
the sergeant will get
a proper send-off today.
Thank you, Officer.
- [groans]
- [nurse 1] Bitch!
What did I say would happen
if you started demanding things again?
- I'm sorry, miss.
- [groans in frustration]
Do you really think
you've been here long enough
to demand schedule changes?
Just take the shifts they give you.
It won't happen again.
[nurse 2 scoffs]
Listen.
One word to the head nurse
and your career is over.
Get that through your thick skull
before you try that shit again.
If she tries it again, just tell me.
- [nurse 1] She's so fucking annoying.
- [nurse 2] Today's snack is dakbal.
[nurse 1] From the same place
as last time?
[nurse 1] Yes, of course.
There's no need to go anywhere else.
[melancholic music playing]
[gun clicking]
[gun clatters]
[tense music playing]
If owning a gun becomes legalized,
we will live in a world
where bulletproof vests
become a necessity,
just as masks were a necessity
during the pandemic!
We now need guns more than ever!
[chanting] Legalize! Legalize! Legalize!
Is this the kind of world
you want to be a part of?
[chanting] No guns! No guns!
[woman 1] The number of protesters
in favor of legalizing gun ownership
has surpassed police estimates of 10,000
and is continuing to grow.
[man 1] As the police prepare
for all contingencies,
they are also dedicating efforts
to pursuing those responsible for…
[woman 2] …out of concern
for a possible clash
and the safety of the people concerned.
[man 2] Blue Brown is behind the protest,
organized through social media.
[woman 3] They are currently looking for
the group's base of operations,
but have no leads at this time.
- [phone buzzing]
- [protesters clamoring]
[tense music continues]
NO CALLER ID
[music subsides]
[footsteps echoing]
[uneasy music playing]
[gun clicks]
You enjoy your tour in the Middle East?
That's why I was chosen?
[scoffs]
At the beginning,
it was all
out of curiosity.
I had such high expectations
of that guy at the gosiwon.
Even though the rules aren't mandatory,
the rules were still made for everyone
to follow. So I thought--
Oh yeah? Why the hell do you care, huh?
I'm fine, really.
I don't wanna cause any trouble.
[breathing shakily]
[dramatic music sting]
But then I heard a police officer
swooped in from the shadows.
Like a superhero on steroids.
So I did some digging on that officer…
TOP SECRET
…and learned he was a person
who knew his way around guns
and how to shoot.
I found out
that now he refused to pick up a gun.
That was ironic.
Tell me. Was that all a facade?
How real was that?
And that's when I felt I truly knew you.
[music fades]
If you were to ever pick up
another weapon,
you'd become a killer again.
[ominous music playing]
And who gave you the right to judge?
We have a few things in common.
We both suffered as children.
We're both obsessed with revenge.
And our lives are defined by guns.
You can't justify your actions
with some sort of grade-school philosophy.
You're nothing but a pimp
peddling guns for money.
All you do is incite fear.
- [music fades]
- [scoffs]
[tuts]
To be honest,
none of that matters to me anymore,
whether or not I sell another gun.
[tense music playing]
Now I'm just curious to see
what'll happen to the little hero in you,
who truly thinks
that… guns aren't the true answer.
[scoffs]
The crazy thing about it, though,
was that it was way easier than I thought.
A gun was the only option they had left.
All that pent-up resentment
and frustration
had to have an outlet.
[Do] Nah, I don't need anything. Thanks.
Excuse me. Something's buzzing on you.
That was the case
with your beloved sergeant,
who was like a father to you.
[tense music continues]
And with Kyeong-suk.
In the end, it was a gun…
I wanna thank you.
…that saved them.
[music swells]
[music fades]
In a world
where the strong devour the weak…
even your bleeding heart
couldn't protect them.
A weapon that allows them to express
how they truly feel is the answer.
That's why putting more guns
into the world will lead to a new utopia.
When everyone has a gun,
then we'll all be like you.
- You're wrong.
- [ominous music playing]
No such utopia exists.
What you're describing
is pure destruction.
People killing and being killed.
[chuckles softly]
That's disappointing.
Of all people…
I thought you would understand the most.
Well,
let's see, shall we?
Who of us is right?
[menacing musical sting]
[tense music playing]
- [protesters screaming]
- [horn blares]
[panicked chatter, screaming]
[protesters murmuring]
What are you doing?
[tense music continues]
I'll show you
the world I would like to live in.
Make yourself at home.
[foreboding music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[elevator door opens]
[gun clicks]
[music fades]
[indistinct chatter]
[man speaking indistinctly]
- [speaker feedback]
- [protesters scream]
[woman] What kind of maniac does that?!
Those are guns you're looking at.
So what are you waiting for?
- [tense music playing]
- Hurry up and take 'em.
It's filled with guns!
[protesters clamoring]
There are guns in here! Come on!
[clamoring continues]
[tense music continues]
Take this!
[men grunting]
- [gunshot]
- [groans]
[automatic gunfire]
[men groaning]
[siren wails]
[officers] Guns are being distributed
from the truck.
Citizens are swarming to it.
[rapid gunfire]
[gunfire stops]
[man screams]
[clamoring continues]
[men yelling]
[protesters screaming]
- Ask Special Ops to send backup.
- Yes, sir.
[dramatic music playing]
[man on TV] Breaking news.
There was a massive distribution
of firearms at today's pro-gun rally.
The citizens became entangled,
quickly descending the rally into chaos.
Police have cordoned off the area
with concerns of a large-scale shootout
taking place.
They've announced they're doing their best
to confiscate all the guns distributed.
We will continue to provide updates
as more information becomes available.
[music fades]
[gun clicks]
[protesters clamoring]
[whistle blowing]
[distant object clatters]
You'd better not stop rolling that camera.
Get it all.
- Okay.
- ["This Is War" playing]
♪ "Welcome to the city" ♪
♪ Said a young man
Sitting next to me ♪
♪ "Heard you're new in town" ♪
♪ "Before you get around…" ♪
Give it to me, God damn it!
♪ "Here's a little tip from me…" ♪
What are we supposed to do
when you take away our freedom?!
- We can't take it anymore! You hear me?
- Just put the gun down.
We're not doing anything wrong!
We just wanna protect each other.
- And you won't say we can't!
- [woman 2] Let's run!
- No. No.
- [woman 1] Leave us alone!
You can't even walk down the street
anymore without getting murdered!
Disrespect! I need this to protect--
- Hey! Grab the gun!
- Get off!
♪ Where the little man
Pays a bigger price ♪
♪ Take another hit
Just get it over with… ♪
FIREARMS DISTRIBUTED AT RALLY
SCENE IN PANIC
♪ Can't stay down no more
We gotta make it known ♪
♪ So get back up
You're not alone ♪
♪ And then hit 'em back
Leave 'em gripping to the floor ♪
♪ You never had a choice
They're knocking at your door… ♪
FIREARMS DISTRIBUTED AT RALLY
SCENE IN PANIC
♪ It's time
And this is war… ♪
UNEXPECTED FIREARM DISTRIBUTION
SPARKS CHAOS AT RALLY
♪ It's time
And this is war ♪
♪ Whoa-oh, whoa-oh-oh, oh-oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh, oh-oh
Oh-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Welcome to the untold ♪
♪ Take a deep breath
Take the higher road… ♪
[Moon Baek] See what I mean, Lee Do?
If, as you say, a world where everyone has
a gun is pure destruction…
[inaudible]
…then why do so many people
want them in their hands?
Isn't it more of a paradise
to give people what they truly desire?
♪ The day has come, my friend ♪
♪ 'Cause this is war ♪
♪ It's time ♪
♪ And this is war ♪
[music fades]
[pin rattles]
- [gas hissing]
- [somber music playing]
[whistle blowing]
- [whooshing]
- [clamoring continues]
[somber music continues]
[Moon Baek] It's this world
that makes people violent.
[footsteps echoing]
All I did was hand them a gun.
I didn't force them to pull the trigger.
The decision has
always been theirs to make.
I didn't pull the trigger for them.
[footsteps echoing]
[clamoring continues]
[gas hissing]
- [tense music playing]
- [exhales sharply]
[Moon Baek] Lee Do.
If a gunshot went off here, right now,
what do you think
would happen to these people?
So was this your plan all along?
[whistle blowing]
[Moon Baek] Not really.
What I really want
is the sound of a single gunshot.
[tense music continues]
One shot
that'll turn this whole place
into a war zone.
Wouldn't pulling the trigger on any gun,
in the pursuit of revenge,
just take control away from the people?
They'd all be afraid
that if they don't have a gun,
they might die.
So everyone would be desperate to get one.
And that kind of society
would kill itself off.
[tense music continues]
[whooshing]
[clamoring continues]
[gunshot]
- [music intensifies]
- [gasps]
- [music fades]
- [Moon Baek breathing heavily]
[protesters screaming, clamoring]
[rapid gunfire]
[stirring music playing]
- [gunfire continues]
- [screaming continues]
[Moon Baek breathing shakily]
- [gunshot]
- [groans]
[grunts]
[gunshot]
[protesters screaming]
[rapid gunfire]
[child sobbing]
[sobbing continues]
[stirring music continues]
[Do panting]
[child sobbing continues]
[sobbing continues]
[boy] Someone help me!
- Mama…
- [whooshing]
[boy breathing shakily]
You'll be okay.
I've got you.
[stirring music continues]
[music fades]
[somber music playing]
GUN DISTRIBUTION SPARKS
ESCALATING VIOLENCE AT RALLY
[male reporter 1] Tragedy struck today
in the heart of the city.
So far,
the mass shooting at Gyeongin Stadium
has reportedly resulted
in more than 70 casualties.
The death toll is sure to increase…
POLICE DISCUSSING EMERGENCY RESPONSE
…seeing as many civilians
have been critically injured.
[male reporter 2] In the midst
of the shooting at Gyeongin Stadium,
a heartwarming image of a citizen
who saved the life of a child.
The citizen protected the child
amidst all the gunfire,
putting his own life in danger.
It is said
he proceeded to comfort the child…
[somber music continues]
[camera shutter clicks]
WE WILL PRAY FOR THE VICTIMS
[somber music continues]
WE WILL REMEMBER THE INNOCENT LIVES LOST
AND WORK TO CREATE A SAFER WORLD
MAY THE VICTIMS REST IN PEACE
[music fades]
ANTI-GUN PETITION
[woman 1] We're collecting signatures
for an anti-gun petition.
- [woman 2] Yes.
- [woman 3] Of course you can.
You just have to sign right there.
ILLEGAL FIREARM DROP-OFF POINT
Thank you for volunteering.
Fine.
Thank you so much.
[Jeong-u sighs]
- You're turning over a handgun, right?
- Yes.
I have no use for it.
You made the right choice.
Sign here, if you please.
PARK SO-HYEON, FEMALE
Very good. Thank you.
[Dae-hyeon] Whoa-ho-ho-ho, man!
The view from this room is amazing.
Yeah, you were right.
Yeah, I could use this room. Yeah.
What?
Why would you censor my article to protect
the victims? Who cares about them?!
I'm telling you right now
if you touch one word without permission,
I'm moving to a different network.
Is that clear?
- [Dae-hyeon sighs]
- [unsettling music playing]
Holy shit! What the hell?!
Do you have any idea
what your article did
to the lives of the innocent?
After I begged
and pleaded to have it taken down?
[Dae-hyeon] Wait, wait. Wait.
I'm the reporter. I'll take it down--
[groans]
[body thuds]
[unsettling music continues]
Given his significant blood loss
and history of cancer,
it'll be difficult for him
to make a recovery.
[unsettling music continues]
[monitor beeping steadily]
[Jake] If you wanna call yourself
a businessman,
you'd better be making five dollars
for every one you spend, at least.
We have an opening.
Proceed as planned.
[unsettling music continues]
[monitor beeping steadily]
[music fades]
[poignant music playing]
I'm good.
Thank you.
[exhales sharply]
[poignant music continues]
[children chatter]
[inaudible]
[music fades]
[funky rock music playing]
[gentle guitar music playing]
[music fades]